Finding Aid for J. Paul Getty Museum Exhibition Photographs, 1980-2004 (bulk 1990-2004) IA20032
Institutional Records and Archives
- Exhibition photographs, 1980-2004; (bulk 1990-2004); Series I.; 14.8 Linear Feet (36 boxes)
  - Exhibitions, 1999
    - "The Making of a Medieval Book,", March 1999-November 2000 (Box 2007.IA.36-11)
      - General installation, March 1999; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-11)
      - Object details, November 2000; (Multiple folders; 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-11)
    - "Dance in Photography,", March 1999; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-14)
    - "Vincent's Irises,", April 1999; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-14)
    - "Faces of Power and Piety: Portraits in Medieval and Renaissance Manuscripts,", April 1999; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-14)
    - "Red Chalk Drawings,", April 1999; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-14)
    - "Edgar Degas: Photographer,", April 1999; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-14)
    - "Dosso Dossi: Court Painter in Renaissance Ferrara,", May 1999; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-14)
    - "Ercole de' Roberti: The Renaissance in Ferrara,", June 1999; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-15)
    - "Picturing the Medieval Family,", June 1999; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-15)
    - "Brassaï: The Eye of Paris,", June 1999; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-16)
    - "From Foundry to Finish: In the Studio of Adriaen de Vries,", July 1999 (Box 2007.IA.36-15)
      - Object details, July 1999; (Multiple folders; B/W 120mm and 4x5 negatives & prints, 4x5 and 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-15)
      - Object details, 1999; (67 slides) (Box 2011.IA.43-01)
      - Making of didactic models, July 1999; (Multiple folders; color proof sheets and negatives, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-15)
      - General installation shots, July 1999; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-16)
      - Digital images of exhibition installation, 1999; (7 color TIFFs on CD) (Box 2011.IA.43-01)
        Access Restrictions
        Use copies do not exist for these digital images. The production of use copies is required before access can be granted and may add a delay to research requests. Advanced notice is required for the production of use copies.
    - "A Passion for Performance: Sarah Siddons and her Portraitists,", August 1999; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-16)
    - "Recent Additions to Collections,", August 1999; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-16)
    - "Taddeo Zuccaro: An Artist's Life in Renaissance Rome,", September 1999; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-16)
    - "Nadar/Warhol: Paris/New York,", September 1999; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-16)
    - "French Manuscript Illumination of the Late Middle Ages,", September 1999; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-17)
    - "Ancient Art from the Permanent Collections,", September 1999; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-17)
    - "Light in the Darkness: The Photographs of Hill and Adamson,", September 1999; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-17)
    - "Juanes to Goya: Spanish Drawings, 1560-1825,", October 1999; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-16)
    - "William Eggleston and the Color Tradition,", November 1999; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-20)
    - "Martin Puryear: Commission for the Getty Center,", December 1999; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-17)
  - Exhibitions, 2000
    - "The Body Beautiful: Artists Draw the Nude,", January 2000; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-17)
    - "Art and Science: Joris Hoefnagel and the Representation of Nature in the Renaissance,", January 2000; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-17)
    - "Adriaen de Vries: Imperial Sculptor,", January 2000; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-18)
    - "Adriaen de Vries: Imperial Sculptor": digital images, 2000; (10 color TIFFs on CD) (Box 2011.IA.43-01)
    - "Poussin Landscapes by Leon Kossoff,", January 2000; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-18)
    - "The Psalms and their Illustration,", March 2000; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-19)
    - "Departures: 11 Artists at the Getty,", April 2000; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-18)
    - "Carmontelle's Transparency: An 18th Century Motion Picture,", April 2000; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-18)
    - "Carleton Watkins: From where the view looked best,", May 2000; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-19)
    - "The Gualenghi-d'Este Hours: Art and Devotion in Renaissance Ferrara,", July 2000; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-19)
    - "The Man in the Street: Eugène Atget in Paris,", July 2000; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-19)
    - "Painting on Light: Drawings and Stained Glass in the Age of Dürer and Holbein,", August 2000; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-20)
    - "German and Swiss Drawings from the Permanent Collection,", August 2000; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-20)
    - Seligman Room and gallery S113 views, August 2000; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-22)
    - "Queen of the Angels,", September 2000; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-20)
    - "Peter Paul Rubens: The Art of Drawing in Flanders,", September 2000; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-20)
    - General installation shots of permanent collection highlighting Ensor and Symbolist sculpture, October 2000; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-19)
    - Gallery views, 2000 (Box 2007.IA.36-21)
      - Galleries S104, S111, February 2000; (Multiple folders; 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-21)
      - Gallery S111, April 2000; (Multiple folders; 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-21)
      - Galleries S103, S104, S111, S112, S114, S115, June 2000; (Multiple folders; 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-21)
    - "Raphael and his Influence Across the Centuries,", November 2000; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-22)
    - "Raphael and his Circle: Drawings from Windsor Castle,", December 2000; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-21)
    - "The Art of Giving in the Middle Ages,", December 2000; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-21)
  - Exhibitions, 2001
    - "Voyages and Visions: Early Photographs from the Wilson Family Collection,", January 2001; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-21)
    - "Statue of an Emperor: A Conservation Partnership,", January 2001; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-22)
    - "Drawing the Landscape,", March 2001; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-22)
    - "Ritual Splendor: Illuminated Liturgical Manuscripts,", March 2001; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-22)
    - "August Sander: German Portraits, 1918-1933,", March 2001; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-22)
    - "Shaping the Great City: Modern Architecture in Central Europe, 1890-1937,", March 2001; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-23)
    - "Preserving the Past,", April 2001; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-22)
    - "To Create a Living Art: Nineteenth Century Drawings,", May 2001; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-23)
    - "Illuminating Color,", June 2001; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-23)
    - "A Royal Menagerie: Porcelain Animals from Dresden,", June 2001; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-23)
    - "Work and Play: Everyday Life in Drawings,", August 2001; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-23)
    - "The American Tradition and Walker Evans,", August 2001; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-23)
    - "Walker Evans and Company: Works from the Museum of Modern Art,", August 2001; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-24)
    - "The Armenian Gospels of Gladzor,", October 2001; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-24)
    - "Posing for Posterity: Portrait Drawings from the Collection,", November 2001; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 120mm and 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-24)
    - "Manuel Alvarez Bravo: Optical Parables,", December 2001; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-24)
    - "Making a Renaissance Painting,", 2001; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-21)
    - "Devices of Wonder,", 2001-2002; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm and 125 color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-26)
  - Exhibitions, 2002
    - "Rome on the Grand Tour,", January 2002; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-25)
    - "Rome on the Grand Tour": digital images, 2002; (7 color TIFFs on CD) (Box 2011.IA.43-01)
    - "Artful Reading in Medieval and Renaissance Europe,", February 2002; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm and 120mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-27)
    - "Railroad Vision,", April 2002; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-25)
    - "Drawing Italy in the Age of the Grand Tour,", May 2002; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-24)
    - "A Treasury of 15th century Manuscript Illumination,", May 2002; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-25)
    - "Dutch Drawings of the Golden Age,", June 2002; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-25)
    - "Gustave Le Gray: Photographer,", July 2002; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-25)
    - "Pieter Saenredam: The Utrecht Work,", July 2002; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm and 120mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-26)
    - "Songs of Praise: Illuminated Choir Books,", September 2002; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-27)
    - "French Drawings in the Age of Greuze,", September 2002; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-27)
    - "Orazio Gentileschi in Genoa,", October 2002; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-27)
    - "Greuze the Draftsman,", October 2002; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm and 120mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-27)
    - "Greuze the Painter: Los Angeles Works in Context,", October 2002; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-28)
    - "The Medieval Bestseller: Illuminated Books of Hours,", December 2002; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-28)
  - Exhibitions, 2003
    - "Mise en Page: The Art of Composing on Paper,", January 2003; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm and 120mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-28)
    - "About Life: The Photographs of Dorothea Lange,", January 2003; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm and 120mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-28)
    - "The Grapes of Wrath: Horace Bristol's California Photographs,", January 2003; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-28)
    - "Bill Viola: The Passions,", January 2003; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm and 120mm color slides, digital images on CD-ROM, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-29)
    - "Five Hundred Years of Manuscript Illumination,", February 2003; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm and 120mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-28)
    - "Prehistoric Arts of the Eastern Mediterranean,", March 2003; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm and 120mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-30)
    - "Between Heaven and Earth: Images of Christ and the Virgin,", March 2003; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm and 120mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-30)
    - "Surrealist Muse: Lee Miller, Roland Penrose and Man Ray,", March 2003; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm and 120mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-31)
    - "Picturing the Natural World,", June 2003; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm and 120mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-31)
    - "Strange Days: Photographs from the Sixties by Winogrand, Eggleston and Arbus,", August 2003; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm and 120mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-30)
    - "Illuminating the Renaissance: The Triumph of Flemish Manuscript Painting in Europe,", September 2003; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm and 120mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-29)
    - "Michelangelo to Vasari: Drawing the Figure in Renaissance Florence,", September 2003; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm and 120mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-30)
    - "The Making of Furniture,", November 2003; (120mm and 35mm color slides) (Box 2007.IA.36-28)
    - "The Making of Furniture,", November 2003; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-31)
    - "Julia Margaret Cameron: Photographer,", November 2003; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm and 120mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-32)
    - "Construction Sights: Photographs of the Getty Villa by Richard Ross,", November 2003; January 2004; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm and 120mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-32)
    - "Images in Light: Newly Acquired Stained Glass,", December 2003; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm and 120mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-32)
    - "Casting Characters: Portraits and Studies of Heads,", December 2003; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm and 120mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-32)
    - "Jean-Antoine Houdon: Sculptor of the Enlightenment,", December 2003; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm and 120mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-33)
  - Exhibitions, 2004
    - "Glory of the Gothic Page,", January 2004; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm and 120mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-33)
    - "Recent Acquisitions: Eugène Atget, Brett Weston, William Garnett, Milton Rogovin,", February 2004; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm and 120mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-34)
    - "Window Onto Spain: Drawings and Prints from Ribera to Goya,", March 2004; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm and 120mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-34)
    - "Photographers of Genius at the Getty,", March 2004; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm and 120mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-34)
    - "Seeking Illumination: Monastic Manuscripts, 800-1200,", May 2004; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm and 120mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-35)
    - "Visions of Grandeur,", June 2004; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm and 120mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-35)
    - "Spirit into Matter: The Photographs of Edmund Teske,", June 2004; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm and 120mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-35)
    - "Transforming Tradition: Ancient Motifs in Medieval Manuscripts,", September 2004; (Multiple folders; B/W negatives & prints, 35mm and 120mm color slides, documentation) (Box 2007.IA.36-31)